日常工作
听译：@Phuckq  压制：感康小快客
校对 & 后期：@Phuckq
退役记
【三次元成瘾者康复中心】倾情奉献
更多动画 新浪@Kresent
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
听听这引擎的轰鸣啊
Listen to that engine purr!
多亏了这辆车
Thanks to the cart,
我们送化肥的时间打破了纪录
we picked up this manure in record time.
是啊老兄
Yeah dude.
一车在手 怂活没有
With this cart, there's no lame job.
本森可以给我们之前招架不住的活儿了
Benson can give us that we can't handle.
对了 说到活儿
Hey speaking of jobs,
我们员工会议要迟到了
we're late for the staff meeting.
给我冲
Punch it.
哟 看看谁终于决定来了
Oh, look who decided to show up.
抱歉 本森
Sorry, Benson.
我刚才说到
As I was saying,
我刚记了记帐 发现今年公园预算有结余
I crunched the numbers and the park has extra money this year.
摩迪凯 瑞格比 你们俩可以把这坨废铜烂铁丢进垃圾箱了
Mordecai and Rigby, you can take this hunk of junk to the dump.
啥
Whuh?
因为我给大家买了这个
'Cause I bought us this.
跟智能小车问个好吧
Say guten tag to the Smarten Karten.
*德语
你好
Guten tag.
现代 精细 强力
Modern, sophisticated, powerful.
被用来形容德国工程设计中的这项奇迹
These are three adjectives used to describe this miracle of German engineering.
这东西足有一百马力
This thing has 100 horsepower!
还有专门放饮料的地方
A device that holds beverages.
不可能 屁屁取暖器
No way! A butt warmer!
谁会需要这些东西啊
Who needs all that stuff?
这里也有形容这辆车的一些词汇
Here are a few words to describe the cart.
可靠 呃 经典
Reliable, uh, classic...
过会就不会闻起来有化肥味了
Won't smell like manure later.
这座位是仿复古风设计
These seats are vintage simulated vinyl.
再看看这些经典的小细节
And look at these classic details.
那些只是贴纸而已
Those are stickers.
本森 这辆车一直就在公园里
Dude, Benson, the cart's been at the park forever.
它就像个家庭成员一样
It's like the member of the family.
它是公园里的第八个员工
It's the eighth worker of the park.
这车的引擎快寿终正寝了
That cart's engine is on its last legs.
它在往空气里排放毒气啊
It's releasing noxious gas fumes into the air.
肌肉男也老往空气里放毒气
We're not taking Muscle Man to the dump
可是我们也没把他当垃圾处理了呀
and releases noxious fumes all the time!
别 他不值得你生气
No! He's not worth it.
你们啊你们
Guys, guys.
我知道你们和这辆车有过很多美好回忆
I know you had a lot of good in that cart.
但养这辆车已经不划算了
But it's not cost effective.
谁来为养护买单呢
Who's gonna pay the bills for it?
我们来买单
We'll pay 'em.
也就是说 油钱你来付
So, you'll pay the gas bill.
妥了
Done
还有维修费
And the repair bills.
更不用说保险费 牌照费
Not to mention insurance, tags,
还有偶尔染上破伤风的打针费了
and the occasional tetanus shot.
好的吧
Okay.
两千刀
$2,000?!
没错
That's right.
你们后半辈子的每个月都要全额付款
Paid in full every month for the rest of your life.
好吧 你赢了
You've made your point.
天黑之前把这车扔掉 不然我就炒了你们
Now take the cart to the dump by the end of the day or you're fired!
我们该动身去垃圾场了
We'd better get going to the dump.
这不公平 老兄 这对车子不公平
It's not fair, man. It's not fair to the cart!
老兄 我也爱这辆车 可是我们没钱养它
Dude, I love the cart too. But we can't afford to keep it.
咱们把饮料倒在车盖上吧 敬车子一杯
Now let's pour soda on the hood, for old cart's sake.
好吧
Word.
这就是有了意识的感觉吗
Is it what it's like to be conscious?
这怎么可能
How is this possible?
含咖啡因苏打水
能量饮料
真是太棒了
This is awesome!
我也很高兴 摩迪凯和瑞格比
I'm happy also, Mordecai and Rigby.
老兄 你认识我们 你叫我们摩迪凯和瑞格比
Dude, you know us? You call us Mordecai and Rigby!
你有名字吗
Don't you have a name?
呃 根据车身内部的信息 我叫...制造
Well according to the writing on my insides, it's...Hecho.
*西班牙语
墨西哥制造
Hecho en México.
我们就管你叫"车车"了
We'll just call you "cart".
哇 我的第一个外号诶
Wow my first nickname!
如果你们不把我丢去垃圾场那就太好了
A lot of good that'll do me, not if you take me to the dump.
我才活了三十秒 就已经感受到了生活的残酷
I've only been alive for 30 seconds and I've already known that life is cruel.
想想吧 我还没感受过哪位车子小姐的爱抚
And to think, I've still never felt a delicate touch of a lady cart.
我受不了了
I can't stand it!
车车 你命不该此
Cart, you deserve better than this.
在你去垃圾场之前 我们会带你领略以往绝对感受不到的事物
Before you go to the dump, we' ll take you to experience all the  things you've never got to do.
真的吗 这算是看在老车的份上
Wow you do that? For old cart's sake?
对啊 看在老车的份上
Yeah dude, for old cart's sake.
那你想做的第一件事是什么呢 车车
So what do you wanna do first, cart?
这个嘛
Well...
车车 我不得不说 你这家伙还真不赖
I got to say cart, you're a pretty cool guy.
彼此彼此 摩迪凯兄
Right back at ya, Brodecai.
摩迪凯 瑞格比 听得到吗
Mordecai, Rigby, are you there?
老兄 老兄 用法国口音回他
Dude, dude, answer in a French accent.
啥 少来了你
What? No way.
喂 本森
Hey, Benson.
等一下等一下 告诉他我们刚去接了他的老娘
Wait wait wait, tell him we just picked up his mama.
老兄 别说了
Dude, shut up!
你们俩几个钟头前就该回来了
You guy were do back hours ago.
抱歉 我们
Sorry, we...
我不管 总之给我回来 不然就炒了你们
I don't care! Get back here or you're fired!
好吧 我们该去垃圾场了
Aright, we'd better head to the dump.
车车呢
Where's cart?
啊 搞什么 他抛下我们了
Ah! What?! Did he ditch us?
不 这就像那次本森要我们照顾他的狗一样
Oh no! This is just like the time Benson had us take care of his dog.
我们把狗带来奇芝后来狗就跑丢了
Then we took the dog to Cheezer's then the dog ran away!
奇芝：剧集中经常出现的快餐店
等等 他在那儿呢
Wait, there he is.
车车 你在干嘛呢
Cart, what're you doing?
抱歉伙计们 我刚扔完垃圾
Sorry guy, I was just throwing away our trash.
就像我也会被那个谁扔了一样 扔去垃圾箱 对吧
Kinda like who's gonna throw me away. You know, at the dump?
拜托 车车 不是你想的那样
Come on cart, it's not gonna like that.
我就只是 一个用过的玉米卷包装袋吗
Is that all I am? Just a... used-up taco wrapper?
你知道什么能让我感觉好点吗
You know what make me feel better?
什么
What?
观赏落日
If I can get a view of the sunset.
是呀 落日会是极品的送别礼物
Yeah, that sunset is prime send-off material!
走起来
Let's Goooooooooooooooooooo.
我可不清楚
I don't know.
拜托了 伙计 再送我一程
Come on buddy, just one more drive.
看在老车的份上
For old cart's sake?
我可不能拒绝这张脸
I can't say no to that face.
哇 这真是 太壮观了
Wow, it's... magnificent.
看到这样的美景让我短暂的一生
Just seeing such beauty gives meaning to my short life,
和有意识后更为短暂的生命都充满了意义
and even shorter life as a sentient being.
我真的觉得非常平静
I really feel at peace.
太好了 老兄
That's great, dude.
好吧 咱们该走了
Alright, let's get going.
你 你知道吗 我还没 还没感受过洗车 对
You... you know I've never been to a... a car wash. Yeah.
可是我们总是清洗你啊
But we wash you all the time!
不 我是说真正的洗车
No I mean a real car wash.
听着 我知道你不是高尔夫球车 你不会懂的 但是
Look I know you won't understand because you are not a golf cart, but...
我不想带着遗憾离开人世
I don't wanna go without experiencing this.
可是我们会湿透的
Then we'll get soaked.
是啊 可是我都要被碾碎了
Yeah... well I'm getting crushed.
大概是我被碾碎前 你们能为我做的最微不足道的事了
Seems like the least you can do, with me being crushed and all.
多谢 伙计们 这对我意义深重
Thanks so much guys, It really means a lot to me.
既然我干净了 就可以去完成最后遗愿了
And now that I'm clean, I'm ready for my final wish.
啥 你说的刚才那件事已经是最后遗愿了
Ah what?! You said the last thing was the last thing.
我保证 这个真的是了 最后遗愿
I promise! This is it! One last wish.
看在老车的份上
For old cart's sake.
行行行 但是到此为止
Okay, fine. But that's it.
好诶
Niiiiice!
走起来
Let's gooooo!
到底要去哪儿啊
Where to exactly?
等会就知道了
You'll see.
说真的 你们俩一定会喜欢的
Seriously, you dudes are gonna love this.
家庭餐馆
Family Restaurant?
"生活娱乐"  "愉快用餐" "乐趣满满"
"自1960年起"
为什么每个字都要打引号啊
Why is everything in quotes?
喂 我说过沙拉另外放 另外放
Hey, I ask for the dressing separate! Separate!
那你就去跟投诉部门讲吧 就在这里
Take it up with the complaints department, right here.
小汪
Puppies!
小喵
Kittens!
小汪
Puppies!
小喵
Kittens!
喂 你们要点啥
Hey, you're gonna order something?
机油 纯的
Engine oil, black.
我懂了 油钱我付
I get it, oil's on me.
老兄 你早该告诉我们你只是想加油了
Dude, you should've just told us you wanna to find a oil change.
喂 你不知道这种水准的油会给你的引擎造成不必要的负担吗
Hey, don't you know that grade of oil causes unnecessary wear impair on your engine?
那就当是我死前心愿喽 老兄
Oh maybe I got a death wish, pal.
你这种没个正经的就该被扔去垃圾场
Jokers like you should be taken to the dump.
你让我想吐
You make me wanna puke!
混蛋
Jerk.
好了 最后一杯你也喝完了
Okay... you got your last drink.
咱们该去垃圾场了 已经不早了
Let's head to the dump, it's getting late.
就这样吗 这可还没完呢
Oh this? This isn't the last thing.
啥 那怎么才算完
Uh?! Then what is it?!
瞧好了
Watch this.
我一直都想要打个架
I've always wanted to get into a fight!
你欠揍啊
Aims fighting words?
我讨厌这首歌
I hate this music!
谁要来试试
Who want some!
车车
Cart!
滚出去
Get lost!
这里是高雅的家族企业
This is a decent family establishment.
不许你们这些人渣来搞破坏
Don't need you low lives of messing things up.
等等 车车哪去了 我就知道 他又抛下我们了
Wait a minute, where's the cart? I knew it, he ditched us!
我们一有机会就该把他扔去垃圾场的
We should've taken him to the dump when we had the chance.
我们肯定要被炒了
We're so fired dude!
摩迪凯 看 这里有汽油的痕迹
Mordecai look, an oil trail!
他在那儿
There he is!
车车 你在这上面干嘛呢
Cart, what are you doing up here?
我 我很抱歉 伙计们 我
I... I am so sorry you guys, I...
我不想你们看到我这狼狈样
I just didn't want you to see me like this.
没关系的 老兄 现在可以跟我们去垃圾场了吗
It's alright dude, can we please just go to the dump right now?
如果我要去的话 也得按我的方式来
If I have to go, I'm gonna do it my way.
我想在这个悬崖上告别 跳进海里
I want to be sent off this cliff, into the ocean.
在第三世界国家产的烟花中 在荣耀之光下一跃而起
Filled with fireworks from a third-world country, to go out in a blaze of glory.
这是我 最后 最后一个愿望
That's my final, final wish.
这是 我听过最酷炫的事情
That's... the coolest thing I've ever heard.
好了 最后一支了
Alright, that's the last of them.
火箭炮
人造爆竹
谢谢你们
Thanks you guys.
你有什么遗憾吗
Do you have any regrets?
虽然我没能写本小说 但我领略过其他车子难以置信的事物
Well I never did write that novel, but I've seen things other carts wouldn't believe.
此处开始 车子的遗言恶搞了《银翼杀手》中的死前独白
我在家庭餐馆打了一架
I've started an all-over board at family restaurant.
我在本市最高的停车场上见证过落日余晖
I've watched sun beams shimmer of the city from the highest parking ramp.
我唯一的遗憾 就是装不下更多烟火了
My only regret, is that I couldn't hold more fireworks.
是啊 不过这也够多了
Yeah, but it's still a lot.
没错
Yeah it is!
让好戏开始吧
Let's get the show on the road.
保重 老朋友
Good luck, old friend.
史上最酷退役
Coolest decommission ever.
酷到不行
Totally cool!
摩迪凯 瑞格比
Mordecai, Rigby.
喂
Hello?
之前记账出了点错
There's been an accounting error.
我忘记加个零了 所以其实我们买不起新车
I forgot to carry a zero and it turns out  we can't afford the new cart.
而且肌肉男70%的屁股都被那个取暖器弄成了三度烧伤
And the seat warmer gave Muscle Man third-degree burns on 70% of his butt.
我要你把那辆老车带回来
We need you to bring the old cart back.
我想你俩肯定很高兴吧 毕竟他也没那么破 对吧
I bet you two're glad to hear that, you know, it wasn't such a bad old cart after all.
咱们去捞他吧
Let's go get him.